WILLIAM BURDICK

Software Engineer

Duluth, GA 30097 • williamfburdick@gmail.com • github.com/WilliamFBurdick • + 1 (330) 592-0546

SUMMARY

Experienced Software Engineer and hobbyist Game Developer, with a focus on low-level programming in C++. Graduated the University of Kansas in 2021 with a Bachelor of Science in Computer Science, with a heavy background in object-oriented programming in C++. Hobbyist game developer, I've worked on many projects in Unity, Unreal Engine, and even creating game systems using C++.

SKILLS

- Languages: C++, C, C#
- Development Environment: Visual Studio 2019, Visual Studio 2022

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

AMERICAN GAMING SYSTEMS

Duluth, GA

Software Engineer I

2022-Present

- Received a 10% increase in pay after 1 year.
- Led development teams in production of 2 tools for game developers and testers, improving performance.
- Fixed over 40 software bugs as a member of the platform team.
- Delivered 2 major platform releases in a CI/CD environment.
- Planned and developed new platform features with an Agile process.

LAKESHIRTS LLC Loveland, CO 2021-2022

Software Developer

- Developed features for new database web tool using C#.
 - Maintained existing VBA-based database software.
 - Diagnosed and fixed IT issues on-site as they arose.

INDEPENDENT EXPERIENCE

Game Development

Developed independent projects in Unity and Unreal Engine. Used C++ and OpenGL to develop simple games and 3D rendering software. Participated in game jams for itch.io.

EDUCATION

UNIVERSITY OF KANSAS

Lawrence, KS

Bachelor of Engineering, Major in Computer Science

2015-2021

Focus on Object-Oriented design and data structures utilizing C++. Efficiency in algorithm solving. Completed software projects with teams of engineers.